Kritika Uma Shankar

Sandy, Utah 84070 • (408) 429-9497

kritikaumashankar@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/kritikaumashankar

Focussed and quick learning Software developer with 3.5 years of experience in programming who is proficient in Java, HTML, CSS and Javascript. Bringing in depth experience in software design, maintenance, as well as the ability to work with new and existing codes.

Education

The University of Utah , Professional Education, Salt Lake City, Utah
 Full-time Web Development Certificate, DevPoint Labs
 08/201

08/2018 - 10/2018

K C G College Of Technology, Anna University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India
 Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics
 09/2006 - 05/2010

Experience

Senior System Engineer Infosys Ltd., Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India 04/2013 - 06/2014 Technologies: Java, Struts, JSP, MS SQL, Javascript, SVN, HTML, CSS

- Collaborated with the on-site team member to understand the business process, gathered
 requirements, analyzed and created the technical design document for **Bulk Email**application (**Bank Of America client**) where different email template is created for
 different downstream applications.
- A schedule job was implemented to store User view, Email click in database from XML in Java
- Enhanced and added new functionalities to the existing application for better UI usage to improve user experience.

System Engineer Infosys Ltd., Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

12/2010 - 03/2013

Technologies: Java, Struts, JSP, DB2, Springs, Javascript, EJB

- Involved in Analysis, Build and Test phase of enterprise application called **Express Pass** (American Express client).
- Optimized the performance of the application by writing DB queries into Stored Procedures.
- Worked on POC for introducing Spring(Dependency Injection) into Epass application. Received appreciation from Team Lead and Project Manager after successfully completing the POC of Spring Dependency Injection.
- Responsible for post production support and maintenance.

Skills

Software: (Proficient): Java, J2EE, Javascript, SQL (Familiarity): React, Spring, JSON, NodeJS(Express), PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST API, Spring Boot, JPA/Hibernate, Ruby, Rails. **Tools:** Tortoise SVN, Eclipse IDE, IntelliJ IDEA, Git, Heroku, AWS(S3 Bucket), Visual Studio Code, Apache Tomcat, Apache Maven.

Projects

Personal Website: www.iamkritika.live

• Developed in React for front-end and Node.js for BackEnd. MongoDB is used to store number of clicks. Nodemailer for sending email.

Flash Cards

github.com/kritikaumashankar/FlashCardsFullStack

- FrontEnd is developed in React. Back End is developed in RESTful and Spring Boot.
- A simple webapp to play flash card game where questions will be displayed and you can guess the answer.Question and Answers can be added, edited or deleted.
- There is a time interval of 5s to display next question and questions are displayed randomly.

Magic 8 Ball:

github.com/kritikaumashankar/Magic8BallRestJava

- Developed in Java and REST API(Jersey).
- Ask a question and random answer is displayed.
- List, add, edit and delete the answer.